Finding Aid for the Alfred Dennis Scripts PASC.0276
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alfred Dennis scripts
circa 1960s-1980s
UCLA Library Special Collections
Dennis, Alfred
PASC.0276
3.0 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Actor Alfred Dennis has appeared on film, television and stage. The collection consists of scripts that appear to be related to Dennis' local and/or community theater involvement.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2002.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9948595323606533
Biography
There is very little biographical information available about Alfred Dennis. As an actor, Dennis has appeared in a number of motion picture, television, and stage productions. Among his motion picture and television credits are The Jerk, The Shootist, Get Smart, Kojak, and The Monkees. Among his theater credits are the Off-Broadway production of One Night Stands of a Noisy Passenger and Kool Aid. Dennis also has been involved in community theater as actor and director with productions such as Cabaret, Can-Can, Show Boat, South Pacific, and Victory Canteen.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of what appears to be play scripts related to the career of Alfred Dennis. Included in the collection are a variety of scripts that appear to be for community and/or local theater productions during the 1960s-1980s. Among the scripts are Cabaret, Can Can, Fiddler on the Roof, Kiss Me Kate, Man of La Mancha, Show Boat, and South Pacific. It is not clear to what extent Dennis was involved with the productions or where they were produced. Additionally, there are occasional clippings and ephemera found with selected scripts.
Organization and Arrangement
The scripts are arranged alphabetically by production title.
Scripts (documents).; Theater -- Production and direction -- Archives.; Actors -- Archives.; Dennis, Alfred--Archives.
- Born Yesterday - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Cabaret - play script, 1966 Nov 20 (Box 3)
- Caesar and Cleopatra - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Call Me Madam- annotated play script, no date (Box 2)
- Can Can - play script, no date (Box 2)
- Can Can - play script, no date (Box 4)
- Can Can - play script, no date (Box 4)
- Carnival - play script, no date (Box 4)
- Cradle Will Rock (The) - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Cyrano de Bergerac - play script, newspaper clippings, playbill, and ephemera, no date (Box 4)
  General note
  Appears to be Cyrano de Bergerac.
- Dame Wiggin's Dilemma - play script and music, no date (Box 6)
- Darling Rodalinda (Fledermaus) - playbills, no date (Box 5)
- Die Fledermaus - dialogue and reviews, 1984 April (Box 5)
- Die Fledermaus - newspaper clippings, L.A. Opera Theater newsletter and program, 1984 April (Box 5)
- Die Fledermaus - opera and score, 1951 (Box 5)
- Die Fledermaus - play script, no date (Box 5)
- Die Fledermaus - rehearsal schedule and dialogue, 1984 March (Box 5)
- Dybbuk (The) - play script, no date (Box 4)
- Fetch Me a Fig Leaf - annotated play script, no date (Box 1)
- Fiddler - stage manager play script, no date (Box 5)
- Fiddler on the Roof - play script, stagebill, clipping, and ephemera, no date (Box 4)
- Guys and Dolls - published play script, 1951 (Box 3)
- Hello Dolly - play script, 1964 Jan 16 (Box 4)
- Help, Help the Globolinks! - published opera vocal score, 1962 (Box 6)
- I Do, I Do - play script, 1966 (Box 4)
- Illya Darling - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Illya Darling - play script, no date (Box 2)
- In a Cold Hotel - play script, no date (Box 1)
- John Dooley - songs and letter, 1961-1967 (Box 6)
- Kiss Me Kate - play script, no date (Box 3)
  Appears to be Kiss Me Kate.
- Kiss Me Kate - play script, no date (Box 5)
- Let's Face It - annotated play script, 1964 Sep 3 (Box 1)
- Little Shop of Horrors - play script, 1982 (Box 3)
- Man of La Mancha - published play script, 1966 (Box 5)
- Man of La Mancha - published play script with introduction, 1966 (Box 5)
- Merry Widow (The) - play script and music, no date (Box 3)
- New Moon - play script, playbill and notes, no date (Box 1)
- Oklahoma - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Oklahoma - play script, no date (Box 3)
- Play That on Your Old Piano - play script, no date (Box 2)
- Ram's Horn (The) - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Royal Crown - Gatorade advertisement project, 1968 Nov 14 (Box 2)
- Show Boat - play script, no date (Box 3)
- Song of Norway (The) - annotated play script, no date (Box 4)
- Sound of Music (The) - published play script, 1960 (Box 3)
- South Pacific - play script, no date (Box 2)
- Student Prince (The) - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Sweeney Todd: The Demon Barber of Fleet Street - photocopied publication, 1979 Mar (Box 3)
- Sweethearts - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Sweethearts - play script, no date (Box 1)
- Take Me Along - play script, no date (Box 4)
- That Hat - play script and ephemera, 1964 Aug 10 (Box 2)
- Theatre Arts publication - six issues, 1952-1959 (Box 6)
- Tovarich - play script and music, no date (Box 6)
- Twin Brothers (The) - Narrative and Lyrics, no date (Box 1)
- Wizard of Oz (The) - play script, no date (Box 2)
  Appears to be the Wizard of Oz.
- Wizard of Oz (The) - play script, no date (Box 2)